天啊 那双手冰凉刺骨啊
Oh,my goodness,those hands are cold.
至少让我做个饱死鬼啊
At least, buy me dinner first.
告诉我的妻子孩子我爱它们
Tell my wife and kids I love them.
天啊
Oh, my god.
你瞬间把故事变黑暗了 妈
That's kind of dark, mom.
什么啊
What
等等 我最爱的医院食物是什么
Wait, what's my favourite hospital food?
哈露[哈啰+吉露果冻]
Jell-o!
好啊 哥们儿
Hi, buddy.
不 今天可以的
No, today is so good.
什么可以 哪个哥们儿
Good for what? Who's buddy?
好啊 直接来屋子里见面吧
Yeah, just head over on to the house.
谁家屋子 哥们儿又是谁
Whose house?who's buddy?
行 一会儿见
OK, see you in a couple.
一对什么 哥们儿是谁
Couple of what? Who's buddy?
肯尼斯
Kenneth.
-肯尼斯 -肯尼斯
- Kenneth? - Kenneth!
如果我有儿子 我想他能和肯尼斯·普洛弗一样
If I had a son, I'd want him to be like Kenneth Ploufe.
你确实是有儿子的
You do have a son.
我们刚搬来这里时
When we first moved in here,
他还是个可爱的小孩 住在我们隔壁
He was the sweet kid who lived next door.
是住在我们隔壁的古怪小孩吧
Mm, the weird kid who lived next door,
但菲尔对他很亲
But Phil always had a soft spot for him
因为肯尼斯有点敬仰他
Because Kenneth sort of looked up to him.
我都不想说他视我如英雄
I wouldn't say hero.
但你还是说了
And yet you did.
因为你不打算说啊
Well, you weren't going to.
克莱尔对肯尼斯有些成见
Claire's always had some issues with Kenneth.
他老是色迷迷地盯着我看
He would stare at me a little too long.
那能怪他吗
Can you blame him?
因为你当年穿得太性感了
You used to dress sexy back then.
一晃十年过去了 难以置信啊
Ten years. Can you believe it?
我觉得刚刚的拥抱过于仓促
I feel like we ended that last hug too soon.
再来一个吧
I-- come on again!
哦 抱的多了点吧
Oh, wow, that's a lot of hugging.
她说得对 为什么要拥抱 明明可以直接...
Oh! She's right. Why hug when you can...
-爷们握手 -爷们握手
- Man-shake. - Man-shake.
我去弄咖啡
I'm gonna get the coffee.
爷们握手
"Man-shake."
没搞错吧
Are we sure?
拉起"门帘"
Roll up the curtain.
我都不知道哪样才更糟
I don't know what's worse--
是他每年感恩节都会参加吃派比赛
That he competes every thanksgiving in a pie-eating contest,
还是他已经9次屈居第二了
or that he's 9-time runner-up.
没有比赛 就不是感恩节了
It wouldn't be thanksgiving without the contest.
当然也是啊
Yes, it would.
我好想说说我的射南瓜故事
I think I have to tell my pumpkin chunkin story.
不不不 你不需要说的
Oh, no, no, you don't have to.
不 我觉得我必须说
No, I kind of think I have to.
有次 小卡和他的朋友们
Once, Cam and his friends
试着将南瓜从足球场的一端射到另一端的
tried to slingshot a pumpkin across a football field.
3秒钟
Three seconds.
3秒种就可以讲完那个故事
That's all he needs to tell that story.
山间大雾弥漫
So the fog was rolling in over the mountains
像是覆盖了一条不祥的毯子
Like an ominous blanket
正当我们准备好弹弓时
As we readied the giant slingshot.
牧师的女儿 洛娜
You know, Lorna, the pastor's daughter,
她很紧张 因为当时已经是宵禁后了
She was nervous because like I said, it was after curfew.
她是个"冒牌天使"
She was a goody two-shoe.
我遇见的牧师女儿里就她是那样的
Only pastor's daughter I ever met that was.
最终我们将南瓜装上弓
So we finally launch the pumpkin,
南瓜在空中飞过 穿越一个个门柱
And it sails through the air, goalpost to goalpost...
穿过球门区 直击停车场
Past the end zone, into the parking lot,
又穿过洛娜父亲车子的露顶
Through the open roof of Lorna's dad's car.
我转身对科迪说
I turn to Cody and I say,
射到那里的几率有多大
"Now what are the chances of that landing there?"
他说 哪里
He says, "Where?"
然后我说
And I say...
牧师的汽车天窗
"The sunroof of a preacher man."
哇哇
Wah-wah
好了 进来吧
Okay, come on in!
瞧啊
Voila!
好吧 眼前是什么玩意儿呢
Ah! Okay, what are we looking at?
真是太棒了 你真有才
It is wonderful. You're so talented.
我真不敢相信你做了这个
I can't believe that you did this.
是吧 我自己欣赏的时候 也口水直流
Yeah, my juices were really flowing on this one.
我们可以在派对结束后观看
Hey, maybe we can watch it later at the party.
或者看橄榄球赛吧
Well, yeah, that or football.
小宝贝 我真为你骄傲
Mi amor, I'm so proud of you.
世界上还有什么是你做不到的吗
Is there nothing in the world that you can't do?
餐桌中央摆饰 就算第一件了
Centerpieces, for starters.
你为什么说他做的一切都很棒
Why do you say everything of his is great,
即便实际上很烂
Even if it isn't?
因为我在给他树立信心
Because I'm building him up.
那是父母的任务之一
That's what parents do.
要我说的话 你做的太过了
Too much, if you ask me.
现在的孩子会过马路 就能得到朵小红花
Kids cross the street nowadays, they get a ribbon.
曼尼已经自信心爆棚了
Manny's got plenty of confidence.
他需要的是对现实的偶尔清醒认识
He just needs a little reality check every now and then.
这玩意儿简直丑伤了
And this thing is a horn of ugly.
嘘
Shh!
我妈妈以前总是批评我所做的一切
My mother used to criticize everything I did.
瞧瞧现在的我
And look at me now.
就是个缺乏安全感的可怜虫
I am a jumble of insecurities.
我不懂
I'm not getting that.
绝对不许打击曼尼
Do not say a word to Manny.
好吧 不过相信我
Fine. But trust me,
如果你告诉他实情 他以后会感激你的
If you told him the truth, he'd thank you later.
像克莱尔和米奇一样吗 他们感谢过你吗
Mm. Like Claire and Mitch? Did they thank you?
暂时还没
Not yet.
但很快就会的
But it's coming.
这里充满了我的回忆啊
Ah! So many memories in this place. Yeah.
你们依然 每次吃麦片的时候都那个吗
Do you guys still have, like, every cereal?
必须的
We have a lot.
当然当然 那是肯定的啦
Yeah! Of course you do. Of course you do.
你们有世上最了不起的老爸
You only have the greatest dad in the world.
你近些年在忙些什么啊
So what have you been up to?
你上大学后 我就没见过你了
I haven't seen you since you went off to college.
事实上 我是被大学上了
Oh, you know, actually, that didn't work out so well.
我四处混了一段时间
I bounced around for a while.
最后在新墨西哥州洗起了盘子
Ended up washing dishes in New Mexico.
看来没有大学文凭
So without the benefit of a college degree,
可以选择的职业很有限啊
I guess your options were kind of limited, huh?
别谈学习 今天过节呢
Ease up. It's a holiday.
是啊 是很艰难 不 不 谢谢
Yeah, it was--it was tough. Oh, no. no, thank you.
-谢谢你 甜心 你真好 -好吧
- Thank you, though, sweetie. You're so sweet. - Oh. Okay.
一开始挺艰难的
It was tough for a while...
后来我跟我室友自己创业了
But then a roommate and I started our own business.
也是餐饮业或清洁行业的吗
Oh, was that also in the dish or cleaning industry?
不不
No. No, no, no.
其实是个小投资公司
It was actually a small investment company.
最初规模很小
Well, small at first.
当了一阵科技的弄潮儿
You know, we rode the tech wave for a while,
然后扩张到电子游戏
then expanded into video games,
游乐场 运动场什么的
amusement parks, sports arenas.
什么牛逼就投资什么
Anything that seemed awesome, really.
我此次回乡是来买小飞艇的
I'm actually in town to buy a blimp.
苍天大地啊
Holy crow.
所以如果当初你上了大学
So if you--if you'd gone to college,
可能要4年之后才会做那些事
you would have done all that just four years later,
或者根本不会
or--or never.
得有人去接艾丽克斯了
Alex really needs to be picked up,
甜心 你去接下她吧
Sweetie. Why don't you go get her?
我还想听听他的创业史呢
I wanna hear more of what he has to say about
快走吧
We're leaving.
肯尼斯 我太为你骄傲了
Kenneth, I am so proud of you.
你真的很成功
You really made it.
确实 我运气好
Well, I did get one pretty lucky break.
早些年 我认识了个贵人
Early on, I met a very special guy
他让我意识到我的所思所言都是有价值的
who taught me that what I thought and said had value.
你是说...
Oh, you mean like--
卢克 听他说
Shh. Luke. Let the man talk.
他鼓励我干什么都得找到乐趣
He encouraged me to always find the fun
并且永远跟着这里走
and follow this thing.
-你的肺吗 -不 我的心
- Your lung? - No, my heart.
直到今天 每做一个决定前
To this day, at every crossroad,
我都会问自己
I ask myself one question--
菲尔·邓菲会怎么做
What would Phil Dunphy do?
至理名言啊
Record scratch!
来电话了
Oh, that's me buzzin'.
是帕丽斯打来的
Oh, it's Paris.
她是我在东京的助理
She's my assistant in Tokyo.
他们没我连个4D游戏图都展示不了
You'd think they'd know how to demo 4-d gaming graphics without my help
完全搞不定 嘿 卢克
They don't. Hey, luke,
马友友拉什么乐器来着
what instrument does Yo-Yo Ma play?
"琴"讲
Um... cello?
他就是翻版的我
He's me...
但却是豪华升级版的
And he's spectacular.
天啊
Oh, my god.
肯尼斯·普洛弗与人共有在巴哈马的度假村
Kenneth Ploufe is part owner of a resort in the Bahamas,
某条游轮巡航线
some cruise line,
以及"蕾丝娇女" 那家内衣公司
And Lacy Fair, that lingerie company.
恶心 我正穿着他家的胸罩呢
Oh! Ew! I'm wearing one of his bras!
看这个 模特坐他腿上合照呢
Look, he's got a model in his lap.
-不是吧 -看看她
- No way. - Look at her.
都是你的错
This is your fault!
你真想一天都躲在家不出去吗
Are you seriously gonna stay in here all day?
我无法面对妈妈
I can't face mom.
我一看见她 就会忍不住坦白从宽的
If I see her, I'm gonna have to confess.
淡定 不过就是有点小凹
Take a breather. It's just a dent.
沉默不是撒谎 好吗
And saying nothing is not lying, okay?
只是让真相自己大白而已
It's just letting the truth speak for itself.
现在不是模糊道义责任的时候
This is not the time for moral equivocation.
我不知道那是什么意思
Okay, I don't know what that means,
也不想知道
and also, don't tell me.
你才是那个以后不能碰车的人
You're the one who's gonna lose her driving privileges.
你怎么能这么冷静
I don't know why you're so calm.
我们只要暂时瞒住妈妈
All we have to do is keep it from mom
一直瞒到她去商店就行了
until she goes to the store.
然后 她发现了的话 也会觉得是在商店撞的
Then, when she sees it, she'll assume that it happened there,
本来也就确实是 所以根本不算撒谎
which it did, so it's not really lying.
听听 你说谎都不打草稿
Listen to you.
你是想成为职业罪犯吗
Are you gonna be a career criminal?
你跟妈妈简直一模一样
Ugh. You sound like mom.
我高中毕业后可怎么办啊
I don't know what I'm gonna do after high school.
我那声"哇哇"是表达对你的支持
It was a supportive "Wah-wah."
不让你冷场
I was trying to save the moment.
"哇哇"那种声音怎么可能表示支持
There's no such thing as a supportive "Wah-wah."
那个声调就是讽刺和侮辱的代名词
A "Wah-wah" By its very nature is vicious and undercutting.
我只是为了替你的故事打圆场
Well, I was just trying to salvage that story, okay?
我叫你别说
I told you not to tell it,
你还是说了 结果场子砸了
You told it, and it died.
没砸 只是他们没反应过来
It did not die. It's a thinker.
小卡 他们在想的唯一一件事就是
Cam, the only thing people were thinking was,
"谢天谢地他总算说完了"
"Thank god this story's over."
好吧 我明白了
Okay. I get it.
我的故事让你觉得丢人有多久了
So how long have I been embarrassing you with my stories?
不不 你没有丢我的人
No, no, no, no. You don't embarrass me.
我爱你的故事
I love your stories, okay?
水塘里的拖拉机
The tractor in the swimming hole?
把贝蒂婶的假发戴到猪崽头上
Aunt Betty's wiglet on the piglet?
卡尔叔说她分不清那些小猪崽
Uncle Carl said she couldn't tell 'em apart.
是吧 好好笑啊 多么五彩斑斓的童年趣事啊
See? Those are funny. You have so many great ones.
农场生活就是如此
Well, that's farm life.
无论下雨或天晴 精彩故事永不停
Rain or shine, there's always a bumper crop of stories.
是啊 我的意思是
Yeah, I'm just saying maybe
你该让那个射南瓜的故事退居二线了
you take punkin chunkin out of the rotation.
你说得也有理 或许我可以...
I guess you're right. Maybe I could just--
是啊 就讲那些真实发生过的事
Yeah, stick to the ones that really happened,
人们都喜欢真实的故事
because people love those.
不好意思 你说什么
Excuse me. What?
我的意思是 真事才更有笑点
I'm--I'm just saying people laugh more at stories that are true.
射南瓜是真人真事
Punkin chunkin is a true story.
有点真实?
True-ish?
不 完全真实
No. True.
是吗
Really?
橄榄球场那么大
The length of a football field,
11月底的密苏里 车的天窗还是开着的?
Through the sunroof of a car that was open in late november in Missouri?
那年秋老虎很猖狂
It was unseasonably warm.
所以山间雾气弥漫?
That explains the fog rolling over the hill.
还有科迪是谁
And who's Cody--
你可以熟到跟他一起射南瓜
Who you're close enough to chunk with
但除此之外却从来没提起过他
but mysteriously only appears in this story?
科迪在沙漠风暴行动中不幸阵亡
Cody was K.I.A. In desert storm.
他是个英雄
He's a hero.
你根本没资格质疑
You know, all this from someone
因为你从来没有发射过南瓜
who's never even chunked a punkin.
我可没丢人丢到家呢
Well, I've never lunked a tunkin, either.
因为 那些都不是真事
You know, these aren't real things.
这样可以吧
This'll work, right?
绝对行 老爸
Totally, dad.
干嘛要用一张长桌呢
Why have one long table
明明可以用4个酒馆小餐桌
when you can use four little ones bistro style?
法国人肯定就是这么过感恩节的
I'll bet this is how the French do Thanksgiving.
你不介意跟你米奇舅舅
You don't mind sitting with your Uncle Mitch
还有外公一起坐吧
And, uh, grandpa, do you?
只要不用看莉莉吧唧嘴 坐哪儿都行
Anything's better than watching Lily chew.
随便一提
By the way,
这就是肯尼斯所说的你老爹的另一面
this is the side of your old man that Kenneth was talking about.
创意十足
Original.
天马行空
Imaginative.
无所畏惧
Fearless.
肯尼斯成为亿万富翁是因为他
So Kenneth became a gajillionaire
常常扪心自问 如果是菲尔会怎么做吗
by asking himself, "What would Phil do?"
是的没错
He sure did.
真是神来之笔啊 对吧
Where did that come from? Right?
可你是原版的菲尔
But you're you.
我们怎么没变亿万富翁
Why aren't we gojillionaires?
为什么你不按照菲尔的想法去做呢
Why don't you do what Phil would do?
菲尔 干嘛不把桌子都拼起来
Phil, why didn't you just put the extra leaves in the table?
我想试着来点好玩的 搞点创意
Trying to have some fun, be creative.
拼成一长桌子吧 亲爱的
One long table, honey.
耶稣最后的晚餐用的就是长桌
If it was good enough for the last supper,
我们也该效仿
it's good enough for us.
关于我做的餐桌摆饰 我有点犹豫了
I'm having second thoughts about this centerpiece.
-别想了 -听他说下去
- Ay, no. - Hear him out.
要是我们带它去菲尔和克莱尔家
I just think if we bring it to Phil and Claire's,
就再也见不到它了是吧
we'll never see it again, right?
是的
That's the plan.
那真让人伤心
Well, that would be sad.
不过这份伤感或许能激发我
Except maybe my sadness will inspire me
创造出更棒的作品
to create something even greater.
记得我做的那副拼贴画吗
Remember that collage I made
是它支撑我们度过了卡特里娜飓风危机
that helped us get through Katrina?
都是你造成的 你明白吧
You did this. You know that.
难道
So...
那就是江湖上闻名已久的手抓饭吗
is this the legendary rice pilaf we've been hearing about?
你自己尝尝
Try for yourself.
以前我每年都做这个
Used to make it every year,
但后来它开始抢走了烤火鸡的风头
but it, uh, started to upstage the turkey.
-不好吃吗 -不至于到难吃
- Something wrong? - Not so much wrong as missing.
只是略显平淡无味
It--it just tastes a little flat.
是吗
That a fact?
我只是觉得可以加些辛香料
I just think with the earthiness of the rice,
来盖过米饭的土腥味
you might want something zesty to set it off.
估计加点孜然能管用
I think this might be a job for cumin.
既然我们在相互交流
You know, since we're sharing
-批评指正 -停停停
- helpful criticisms-- - no, no, no, no.
谁都别再说了 曼尼 去换衣服
nobody's sharing anything. Manny, go change for the party.
可是我愿意听取善意的批评
No, no, no, but I appreciate helpful criticisms.
我觉得知道真相十分重要
It, uh, it's important for me that I hear the truth.
能令我更坚强
Makes me stronger,
而不只是个离不开妈的孩子
less of a mama's boy.
没错 妈 他承受得了
Yeah, mom, he can take it.
他嘴巴上这么说
That's what he says,
可你不知道他内心实际的感受
but you don't really know what he feels underneath.
有些人太过敏感
Some people are so sensitive,
一句批评
that they hear one criticism,
就能毁掉他们的才华
and it kills the spark that made them special.
我明白是怎么回事了
I think I know what's going on here.
太好了
Good.
是有关你和你妈之间的纠葛 对吧
This is about you and your mom, isn't it?
对 没错
Yes, it is.
不 不是的
No, it isn't.
就是那样
Yes, it is!
曼尼 别再让我心烦了
Manny, don't upset me anymore.
去 换衣服去吧
Go. Go change.
我该穿什么啊
What--what should I wear?
你穿啥都好看
Ay, you look good in everything!
你去哪儿啊 妈妈
Where you going, mom?
得去趟商店
Mm, I gotta run to the store.
有人把棉花糖都吃完了
Someone ate all the marshmallows.
能跟你商量点事吗
Hey, can I tell you something?
我在考虑寒假以后
I was thinking that maybe after new year's break,
我们可以去其他的大学看一看
we could visit a couple more colleges.
-你说真的吗 -我之前对你太凶了
- Seriously? - I was so hard on you before.
抱歉 我明白我做不到肯尼斯那样
I'm sorry. I know I'm no Kenneth.
我得尽量取得别人的帮助
I'm gonna need all the help that I can get.
亲爱的 我为你骄傲
Honey, I am so proud of you. Oh.
谢了
Oh, thank you.
什么呀
What's this?
-好吧 -怎么了
- Oh, okay. - What are you doing?
米奇舅舅已经在买棉花糖了
Oh, uncle Mitch is picking up the marshmallows.
话说回来 去欧洲背包游
Then again, backpacking through Europe
也有其独特的教育意义吧
could be educational in its own way.
别 别 别
No! No, no! No, no, no!
你知道在欧洲什么算违法吗
Do you know what's illegal in Europe?
啥都不违法
Nothing!
你上大学上定了
You are going to college!
好吧 随你
Okay, fine.
当然是听我的
Darn right it's fine.
手到擒来
Piece of cake.
我头发都要吓掉了
My hair's coming out!
亲爱的 我以为你会布置得简单点
Wow, honey. I-I think you could make these simpler.
将一边平铺开就可以了
Just, you know, sort of do 'em flat and on the side.
就像你希望我成为的那样
Hmm. Yeah. Seems like that's how you like me.
平平淡淡 甘居下游
Flat and on the side.
有时我也需要膨胀一下 摆摆架子
You know what? Sometimes I need to be puffed up and frilly.
要是以后人家问起
All right, is this one of
咱俩婚姻破裂前的征兆之一
those moments I'm gonna have to remember later
我是否就该想到此时此刻呀
when they ask me if there were any signs?
这就是菲尔会做的事
This is what Phil would do--
把餐巾折得有模有样
Make fantastic napkin origami
令客人们又惊又喜
that startles and delights his guests.
我知道 可亲爱的
I know, but, sweetie,
它们看起来有点...
they're just looking a little...
克莱尔 你总是这样 你总打击我
Claire, you always do this. You squelch me.
每当我要展翅高飞时 你就打击我
You squelch me right when I'm about to soar.
亲爱的 你只是折个餐巾而已
Honey, you're folding napkins.
你在屈折我的梦想
You're folding my dreams!
你知道肯尼斯说了什么吗
You know what Kenneth told me?
他事业成功的奥秘
The secret to his success--
是因为他试着模仿我
his whole career, he's tried to emulate me.
唯一不同的是
The only difference is,
没有人不停地要他别干这个 别干那个
he hasn't had someone constantly telling him what not to do.
你意思是说我们家买不起小飞艇的唯一原因
So the only reason we don't have a-a blimp tethered to our mailbox
是因为我总是打击你的"奇思妙想"
is because I'm always shooting down your great ideas?
没错
Yeah.
咱们回顾一下"打击史" 菲尔
Let's review the squelch pile, Phil.
比如 米布丁的特许经销权
Let's see-- the rice pudding franchise.
无齿之徒 也可享受
Works for all chewing abilities.
成人三轮车
Adult tricycles.
有种你就摔摔看
Just try to fall off.
阿司匹林喷射枪
The Aspirin gun.
有人就是吞药困难嘛
Some people have a hard time swallowing!
你还忘说了一个
And you left one out. Hmm.
亲爱的克莱尔 那才是挠破头皮才能想到的
And that, my dear claire, is a real head-scratcher--
"不求人"
"Tm."
开演
Action.
朋友好啊
Hey, friend.
看上去你今天上班累惨了吧
You look like you had a rough day at the office.
在"机器人暗杀工厂"的工作压力真是...
The stress from my job at the robot assassin factory...
生命中不能承受之重
Is too much to take.
给我来一枪阿司匹林吧 亲
Aw, shoot me an aspirin, pal.
日后再议
Maybe someday.
不过先来试试这个合不合适
But until then, try this on for size.
即将拥有32项专利的脑神经导体按摩仪
The real head-scratcher features 32 patent-pending "Nogginizers"
轻柔按摩您的头部
That gently massage your scalp
在安宁的声音中给您以享受
In a soothing purr of motorized delight.
哇塞 真舒服
Ahh. It feels great,
外形也很帅气哦
And it looks good, too.
真是居家旅行必备良器
It's a real lifesaver.
您是说真正的头部按摩仪吧
You mean a real head-scratcher?
"不求人"
"Tm."
我爱你 菲尔
I love you, Phil,
-但是呢 -别说了
- But you-- - Stop.
我就爱听你说爱我
I love your "I love you."
但我就怕温柔背后的一刀
I'm getting awful tired of your "But."
我经历过的
I heard it.
欢迎欢迎 热烈欢迎
Welcome, welcome, welcome!
欢度火鸡节哦
Happy turkey day!
哇 你们买了辆新车啊
Hey, is that a new car?
没错 是不是特棒
Yep! It's the best, isn't it?
我的目光简直被钉在上面了
I can't take my eyes off it.
您也别往别处看了
You shouldn't, either.
你还好吧 闺女
Are you okay, mami?
我 我
I'm... I'm...
大家好啊 派对开始了 快进去吧
Hey, guys! Now the party's started. Come on!
-最近好吗 -很好
- How are you? - Good.
恶心死姐了
You disgust me.
饿坏了吧
Are you hungry?
还好没散架
Oh, good. It's still in one piece.
你都快把我建的洞穴弄塌方了
You hit those potholes pretty hard.
你难道没看见吗
It's like you didn't see 'em.
不 我看见了
No, I saw 'em.
我能跟你说句实话吗 杰
Can I be honest with you, Jay?
我觉得
I'm getting the sense
你好像不那么喜欢我做的"阿雷古丽娜"
that you're not the biggest fan of "Allegria"?
你还给它起了个名字 真棒
You got a name for it now? Great.
好吧 要我说实话
All right. Cards on the table?
你可以做得更好的
This is not your best work.
听着 别会错意
Now look, don't get me wrong.
你挺有才的
You're a talented kid.
终有一天你会展翅翱翔
You're gonna be a big success in the world.
但这个 纯粹是瞎胡闹嘛
But this... this is a swing and a miss.
-不过妈说 -你妈说很好 我知道
- Well, but my mom said it was-- - It's great, yeah, I know.
不过你注意到她的语气了吗
But how did she say it?
什么意思
What do you mean?
"很好"和"还好"简直是天壤之别
There's a big difference between "It's great," and "It's great."
你听出来了吗
You hear that?
"很好"和"还好"
"It's great," And "It's great."
我只知道很多人都说我很有才
All I hear is a bunch of people telling me I'm great.
这就是问题所在了 因为很多时候
And that's a problem, because a lot of times
人们怕你伤不起 故意说谎骗你
people will lie to you to protect your feelings,
那对你完全没好处的
And that's not doing you any favors.
如果想走得更远
You get a lot farther in life
就必须明白自己的优势和劣势所在
if you know what you're good at and what you're not.
现在能接受了吗
Now you can handle that, right?
-恩 -就知道你可以的
- Yeah. - Of course you can.
你还好吧 亲爱的
How you doing, honey?
还好啦
I'm great.
好了 大伙儿 动起来
Okay, everybody, come on!
还有两分钟开伙 准备好哟
Two minutes till dinner! Get ready!
好啊 真棒
Good! All right!
哇塞 曼尼 手上端的什么啊
Oh, wow, Manny. What have you got there?
他亲手做的餐桌装饰哦
He made a centerpiece!
-真了不起 -令人震惊
- Oh, that's fantastic. - It's stunning.
就是个垃圾
It's garbage.
别别别啊
No, no, no!
你干什么呀 多漂亮啊
What are you doing? It's so beautiful!
别骗我了
Stop the lies.
杰跟我说实话了
Jay told me the truth.
你胡说些什么了
What did you say?
我就说他可以做得更好啊
I mentioned it wasn't his best effort.
他说我那是瞎胡闹
He said it was a swing and a miss.
为什么 为什么你要泼冷水啊 杰
Why?! Why do you say these things, jay?!
你简直跟我老妈一模一样
It's like I married my mother!
杰 你为何那样啊
Jay, why would you do that?
他们家人都这德行
Because he's a Pritchett.
不过别被那些小人打击到 曼尼
But don't let these negative nellies drag you down, Manny,
总有一天 你会想出个点石成金的创意
Because one day you could have a trillion-dollar idea
-那些理应最爱你的人 -够了菲尔
-that the people who supposedly love you most-- - Okay, Phil!
别说了 去拿你的头部按摩仪吧
That's it. Go get the head-scratcher.
真正的挠头仪 "不求人"吗
The real head-scratcher, "Tm"?
去拿过来 让大伙儿瞧瞧
Go get it, and let everybody else decide
我耽误了你挣多少金子
how many trillions I've cost you.
多到你想都不敢想
Way ahead of you.
什么状况啊
What's going on here?
我们要书写帽子的新历史了
We are about to make hat history.
我更愿意称之为"帽史"
Or as I like to call it, "Hatstory."
先民们无所事事 终日可以自挠头皮
Early man had hours and hours to scratch his weary head.
而今快节奏社会 哪来时间挠
But what about today's busy times?
谢谢你 小卢子
Thank you, squire.
这项伟大的发明妙在何处
Great thing about this?
你可以何时何地都戴上
You can wear it anywhere.
开秀吧 伙计
Hit it, buddy.
我靠
Oh!
就像成千上万的小天使
It's like a thousand tiny angels
在我的头皮上开舞林大会...
are line dancing on my sca--
我去 似乎头部按摩仪出了点小故障
I... it looks like we got a slight malfunction in a rear nogginizer.
不要啊 快关了 快关了啊伙计
Oh! Shut her down! Shut her down, buddy!
-停不了啊 -一剪没啊 发如血啊
- It's not working! - My hair! It's got my hair!
好吧 算了
Okay! Fine.
我没事
That--I'm fine.
去他妈的神奇功能吧 简直是刺破头皮的
Forgot about that feature. It's an exfoliating... scrub.
儿子 给老爸把安全剪拿来
Buddy, can you grab the safety shears?
我告诉你 菲尔 坚持就是胜利
You know what, Phil? Keep it up.
同是天涯沦落人
And I admire you and Manny.
我明白被心爱的人质疑的滋味
I know what it's like to stare down skepticism from a loved one.
小卡 现在不是时候
Cam, not now.
有什么不行 感恩节良辰吉日啊
Why not now? It's thanksgiving.
家人团聚 问题爆发
Families gather. Issues come up.
问题也是你提出来才有的啊
Only if you bring them up.
打开天窗说亮话对谁都好
It's healthy to get things out in the open.
你们都听过我的射南瓜轶事吧
Y'all know my punkin chunkin story,
要不要我再帮你们复习一下
or do you need a refresher?
-我们听过 -好几遍呢
- We've heard it. -Oh, several times.
我喜欢那个故事
I love it.
是和科迪还有别的朋友一起的那个吗
With Cody and the friends?
没错 所以你们知道故事结局吧
Yes. So you know how it ends.
但问题是 觉得我瞎编的举手
But the question is, who here thinks I made that up?
看吧 简直是泾渭分明 清清楚楚啊
Oh. Well, doesn't that tell the whole story right there?
这边是我们的怀疑派 打压别人梦想的人
Here we have the skeptics, the dream-squashers...
普里契特一家
the Pritchetts.
而这边是梦想家 艺术家和有远见的人
And here we have the dreamers, the artists, the visionaries.
苍天大地啊
Sweet Caroline!
难道要让我们相信
So we're supposed to believe that
你让一个南瓜飞过了整个足球场
you make a-a pumpkin fly across a football field.
对 我现在就能证明给你们看
Yeah. I can prove it to you right now.
我们去足球场
Let's go to the football field.
行 去就去 我希望争议就此结束
Yes! Let's do this. I'd love to end this.
就是 我们去比试一场吧
Yeah! Let's settle this!
梦想家对普里契特一家
Dreamers versus Pritchetts!
太棒了 我说南瓜你说射
Bravo! Bravo! When I say "Punkin," You say "Chunkin"!
-南瓜 南瓜 -不 停下来
- Punkin! Punkin! - No, no, no!
站住 我做了8个小时的饭菜
Hold it! I did not just cook for eight hours
不是为了让你们跑出去证明些愚蠢的观点
so you people could run off to prove some asinine point
输掉的那一方会很难过的
that's only gonna make half of us feel bad!
拜托 尊重下我的劳动成果好吗
Come on! Show a little respect.
火鸡闻起来很香 亲爱的
Turkey smells great, sweetheart.
那是火鸡吗
Is that turkey?
我怎么觉得闻起来像鸡味[胆小鬼]
Because something smells like chicken.
-好吧 我们一决胜负吧 -太好了
- Okay, let's settle this. - Yeah.
大家来吧 杰 我开车
Vamos, vamos! Jay, I drive!
我说南瓜你说射
When I say "Punkin," You say "Chunkin"!
南瓜 射
Punkin! Chunkin!
简直是我经历过最酷的事儿
This is the coolest thing ever.
我要录下来
Okay, I want to film.
不 等一下 我也要露个脸
Ay, no, wait, I want to be in it.
小卡 你确定这样可以吗
Hey, Cam, are you sure this is going to work?
天呐 你说话的语气和科迪一模一样
Oh, god, you sound just like Cody.
你觉得这个可不可以用来发射一个人
Do you think this could launch a human?
卢克
Luke...
-我们还是先发射南瓜吧 -好
- Let's do the pumpkin first. - Okay.
他们在那儿玩的真开心
They're having fun over there,
但最后肯定是悲剧结尾
but you know it's gonna end in tears.
对 向来都是
Yeah, always does.
敲门敲门 谁啊
Knock-knock. Who's there?
物理学
Physics.
-谢谢 -不用
- Thank you. - Mm-hmm.
谁应该来发射它
Who's gonna be able to launch it?
我觉得是小卡
I think it should be Cam!
哦不 我觉得应该是我们所有人一起
Oh, no! I think it should be all of us!
所有人 所有人
All of us! All of us!
到这儿来 哇
Just get right here. Whoo!
我必须声明 我没有打压菲尔所有的梦想
For the record, I don't squash all of Phil's dreams.
只是那些 可能会 注定悲剧的
Just the ones that are, you know, potentially fatal.
我只是想让那孩子准备好来面对现实生活
I'm just trying to get the kid ready for life.
对 如果我们不对他们狠一点
Yeah. Yes, I-if we didn't do this to them,
在社会上也会撞得鼻青脸肿
the world would.
好 大家各就各位准备好要发射了吗
Okay, everybody, in final launching positions?
准备接受羞"乳"吧
Get ready to eat some crow!
羞"乳"的味道可不怎么美味哦
It is not as delicious as it sounds.
好
Okay...
一
Uno!
二 三
Dos! Tres! Three!
怎么回事 小卡
What happened, Cam?
我不知道 我 我不知道
I don't know. I-I don't know.
我们再试一次行吗
Can we do it again?
不 我们只有一个南瓜
No, we only had one pumpkin,
而我们刚刚发射掉了
and we just chunk it.
-就说嘛 我们是对的 -哈 是的
- Well, we were right. - Aw, yeah.
对不起
I'm sorry, guys.
通常我们赢了应该更开心才对啊 对吧
This usually feels a little better, doesn't it?
-是的 -是吧
- Yeah. - Huh? Mm.
好吧 虽然我不愿意承认这点
All right. I-I hate to admit it,
但是当他们把南瓜放进去的时候
but when they put the pumpkin in,
我有一点希望他们能成功
I was kind of hoping it would work.
-是的 -我也是
- Yeah. - Me, too.
好吧 开始幸灾乐祸吧
All right! Let the gloating begin.
你知道吗 其实是一次好的尝试
You know, it was a pretty good try.
我们不需要你们的同情
We don't need your pity.
我们清理一下球场吧
Let's just get this stuff cleaned up.
或者 或者我们可以
Well--or if--if maybe we, um...
-试一下用更大的倾斜角发射 -是的
- We launch it from a steeper angle? - Yeah.
然后 如果你们能有多一些人
Then...maybe if you had somebody else,
一起帮你们拉它
you know, helping you pull the thing.
但是我们没有多余的南瓜了
But we don't have any more pumpkins.
那很简单
That's the easy part!
街坊邻居家家户户门前都有
They're on every porch up and down the block.
-我们可以搞定 来吧 -是的
- Oh, we can handle that. Come on, kid! - Yeah.
来吧 让我们再试一次
Come on. Let's try one.
好吧 我们再试一次
Okay! All right! Let's do it!
我说南瓜大家说射
I say "Punkin," Gang says "Chunkin"!
这个世界上有梦想家 也有现实主义者
There are dreamers and there are realists in this world.
你可能会觉得梦想家们喜欢聚在一起
You'd think the dreamers would find the dreamers
现实主义者又聚成另外的小集体
and the realists would find the realists,
但是往往 二者喜欢混搭在一起
but more often than not, the opposite is true.
如果这个成功了
Maybe if this works,
我们下一个应该发射我做的餐桌装饰
we should launch my centerpiece next.
它没有那么糟糕啦
It wasn't that bad.
你做的手抓饭倒是挺糟糕的
Your rice pilaf was.
杰 小心点儿
Jay, be careful!
好的 准备
Okay. All right.
好 好 继续用力 继续用力
Oh! Oh! Keep going, keep going! Keep going!
其实 梦想家需要现实主义者
You see, the dreamers need the realists
提醒他们 不要把梦想放飞得过高
to keep them from soaring too close to the sun.
而现实主义者
And the realists...
如果没有梦想家的话
Well, without the dreamers,
可能永远无法将梦想放飞
they might not ever get off the ground.
好 下一个一定会穿过球门
Okay! Next one's going through the--the goal thingy,
我能感觉到
I can feel it!
当洛娜 科迪和我做这件事的时候
Now when Lorna, Cody, and I did this, it was--
少说话 多用力
less talkin', more chunkin.
妈妈 我要告诉你一件事
Mom, I need to tell you something.
是什么 宝贝
What is it, honey?
准备
Ready!
海莉开车的时候 我让她分心了
I distracted Haley while she was driving,
我们把你的车撞出了一个凹痕
And we dented your car.
发射
Fire!
姑娘们
Well, girls...
再忍三秒 就追究不到你们头上了
Three more seconds, and you would have gotten away with it.
现在射人了吧
Now a human?
过来吧 莉莉
Come here, Lily.
卢克 别犯二
Luke, no.